

Marco Maida Computer scientist



13 August 1994



github.com/marcomaida



00marcomaida00@gmail.com

About me ———

I am a computer scientist currently pursuing a PhD at Max Planck Institute for Software Systems.

I was born in Turin, Italy, and have been tinkering with computers for as long as I can remember. In 2013, I started working professionally as a programmer. After three years, I decided to start a bachelor degree in Computer Science, while I kept working part-time as game developer. Once I graduated, I moved to Kaiserslautern, Germany, and started a Master+PhD program.

I completed all my master courses, and recently published my first work.

Languages ———

L'italiano è la mia lingua madre,

I am very fluent in English,

und ich spreche auch etwas **Deutsch**.

Extras —

I like doing new and many things, especially if they involve science, nature, music, sport, food or traveling • I usually risk it, if I believe I am right • Probably sometimes I talk too much • I play guitar and — less successfully — sing.

Skills

I have nine years of professional experience in writing code. I am fluent in writing **Python**, **C#**, **C++**, **C**, **Java**, **Rust** and **Coq** code. During my seven years in the **industry**, I learn to work on big code bases in large and small teams.

Having spent two years in **research**, I can study complicated problems and then design, implement, evaluate, document and finally present my solutions.

I am very **outgoing** and, in my experience, I **do well in teams**. Being a relevant part of my career in game development, I am used to collaborate with different professional figures and over time I developed a good sense of aesthetics.

Education

since 2019	Ph.D. student Real-time Systems group	Max Planck Institute for Software Systems
since 2019	Master in Computer Science	Technische Universität Kaiserslautern
2016-2019	Bachelor in Computer Science (110/100 cum laude)	Università degli studi di Torino
2015-2016	Game dev: Software Development (30/30)	t Event Horizon School
2008-2013	Diploma in Computer Science (98/100)	ITIS A. Avogadro

Experience

since 2019 **Computer Science Researcher.**

Max Planck Institute

I am currently working on Real-time Systems. My work is focused on timeliness certifications in safety-critical systems using formal verification (Coq) and on trace-based schedulability analysis on Linux.

2016-2019 Game developer.

34BigThings

I worked with Unity3D (C#) and Unreal Engine (C++) on single player and online multiplayer games shipped on Steam, PS4, XboxOne, Nintendo Switch and mobiles. I developed gameplays, AIs, tools and UIs.

2016 Freelance Unity3D developer.

Teoresi, Choralia, Maserati

I worked as a freelance developer, building interactive visualization software and a learning game using Unity3D and shipping on mobile

devices and browsers.

2013-2016 Software engineer.

R.O. st

I worked as a software developer using C++, C/CLI, C# and SQL building software solutions for glass processing factories. In this company I covered many roles, including traveling to customers to sell, install and teach our softwares.

Other Projects

2018 Fast Mobile Cycle (FMC) Framework and Toolkit.

I developed an open-source Unity3D framework to quickly develop production-ready mobile games. The framework restricts the game type to infinite-runners, but imposes no restriction on the actual gameplay, and automatically handles data persistence, ads, analytics, and a leveling system. Complementary to this, I developed a Python toolkit to automate the creation and updating of the FMC games. With a small team composed of me, an artist, and a designer, we developed ten production-ready games within a month. (www.github.com/34OpenThings)

2017 Razer Chroma in Unreal Engine 4.

I developed a framework that connects gameplay with Razer's Chroma devices, used today in every 34BigThings game.

(www.youtube.com/watch?v=AihLBrJBufk&ab_channel=34BigThings)